威震天？
Megatron?
看来你侦测到的远古汽车人信号是准确的
It seems you've detected the ancient Autobot frequency precisely because it was unearthed.
他们已经把东西挖出来了
没关系 我们的后援快到了
Well, our backup shouldn't be far behind.
在不知道霸天虎挖出何物的情况下
Without knowing what the Decepticons have exhumed
我不愿意再等下去了
I do not think I am willing to wait.
给我看看
Show me.
拿过来给我 千万小心！
Bring it to me. With utmost care!
威震天
Megatron!
我不允许你窃取汽车人的遗产
I cannot allow you to pilfer Autobot relics.
你颠倒了黑白 擎天柱
Not only are you misinformed, Optimus.
另外我建议你放下武器
But I would strongly advise you to lower your weapons.
除非你想跟我同归于尽
Unless you're in the mood for mutually assured destruction.
这不可能
It can't be!
火种剥离器…
The Spark-Extractor.
其貌不扬…
Rather unassuming...
却能将它作用范围内的火种尽数吸走
yet capable of extracting every Spark within its radius.
再想到是你引领我得到它的… 擎天柱
And to think that you led me straight to it, Optimus!
噢…或者我应该说 是奥利安・派克斯
Or should I say, Orion Pax did.
你真应该好好留着你的霸天虎标志
You really should have left your Decepticon shield intact.
你根本想不到 在我们短暂的蜜月里 你的密码破译技术帮了多大的忙
For you have no idea how useful your code-breaking skills proved to be, during our all too brief time together.
声波 打开环陆桥！
Soundwave! Send the Groundbridge.
消灭他们！
Engage them!
大黄蜂 夺回火种剥离器！
Bumblebee! Secure the package.
什么？！
What?!
特技不错嘛 哈
Loop-de-loop, hah.
你的漆蹭掉啦 大黄蜂
You have some brass bearings, Bumblebee.
擎天柱
Optimus
这儿
here.
这是我们探测到的古老频率的来源
The source of the ancient frequency we detected.
是铁堡所用的定位信号
An Iacon homing beacon.
这上面为什么会有汽车人的定位器？
What's an Autobot locator doing on THAT?
战时收缴的霸天虎A级兵器 都被封存在铁堡的地下室里
The class "A" Decepticon weapons confiscated during the War were sealed within the vaults below Iacon.
就是你曾担任档案员的地方
Where once you worked as an archivist.
铁堡不仅是文化中心 还是战时要塞
Iacon was both a cultural center and a stronghold.
在汽车人萎靡不振之际 威震天袭击了铁堡
Which Megatron raided when Autobot troops were at their nadir.
考虑到铁堡可能沦陷 明智的选择是
It stands to reason that in anticipation of Iacon being overrun by enemy forces
遗弃这些武器 以免落入霸天虎之手
these weapons were jettisoned off-world to keep them far from Decepticon reach.
显然 这个定位信号
Clearly, the beacon was added as a safety measure
是这些武器被敌方发现时的防范手段
should the weapons ever be found by the undesired party.
多亏了我们的特技小子 这一个被我们收回了
Well, thanks to our hot-shot stunt driver this one is going in our vault.
你觉得威震天从你那里得到的情报是否只有这些？
Do you think this is the only intel you supplied to Megatron?
阿尔茜 你问的很对
Arcee, you are right to ask.
可惜的是我…不记得了
And I am afraid I... do not remember.
擎天柱
Optimus.
威震天确实在你失忆时利用了你
Megatron clearly took advantage of your amnesia.
但就我们目前所知 只有这个火种剥离器而已
But for all we know this Spark-extractor is the extent of it.
他向你暗示还有其他东西 也许只是为了扰乱你的判断
Have you stopped to consider that he might have suggested otherwise merely to plague your thoughts?
火种剥离器原本已经到手了！
The Spark-extractor was in my grasp!
当初真应该杀了那个侦察兵
I should have removed more than that scout's voice-box
而不是只毁掉他的发声器！
when I had the chance!
没错 声波
Indeed, Soundwave.
奥利安走之前留下的坐标还有两个
We possess two more sets of coordinates which Orion decrypted before departing our ranks.
看看我们还能找到哪些失落已久的宝藏
Let us see what other long lost treasures we might be re-united with.
是的 我刚刚收到了相同的信号
Yeah. I just picked up the same signal.
可能又是一个定位信号
Could be another homing beacon.
我们在坐标处集合
Let's rendezvous at the coordinates.
塞拉斯 另有一个目标在向我们靠近
Silas. Another one's headed to our position.
预计…两分钟后抵达
Estimated arrival - two minutes.
加快动作
Work briskly.
原来这信号是个陷阱
It would appear the signal was a trap.
还好是大黄蜂 不是我
Better Bumblebee than me.
支援部队提前到了
The backup is ahead of schedule.
还算走运
As luck would have it
我干完了
so am I.
收队
Move out.
小蜂！
Bee!
这是谁干的？虎子？！
Who did this? 'Cons?!
我们追上去就知道了 快走！
One way to find out. Come on!
到底走不走啊？！
We rolling’ or not?!
你不能？什么意思？
What do you mean, "you can't"?
你一定能修好小蜂的 是吧？
You can fix Bee, can't you?
大黄蜂伤得很重
Bumblebee was hit pretty hard.
震荡射线可能击穿了他的变形齿轮
The stun blast may have fried his T-cog.
那是一种变形关节吗？
Is that like a T-bone?
不完全是
Not exactly.
是我们用来扫描车辆和变形的器官
It's the organ that allows us to scan vehicles and transform.
火种源在上！
By the Allspark!
大黄蜂的变形齿轮不是损坏
Bumblebee's T-cog isn't damaged.
而是不见了！
It's missing!
但霸天虎也会变形
But the Decepticons transform too.
他们偷它干什么呢？
Why would they steal that?
虽然威震天唤醒过僵尸 但他不会偷器官
Megatron may be known to raise zombies but he is no ghoul.
如果不是威震天干的 会是谁呢？
If Megatron wasn't behind this then who was?
把打击拆掉的那群人
The ones who cannibalized Breakdown.
他们还想挖出我的心
And tried to gut me!
机械党
M.E.C.H.
看来他们对塞博特恩人的生理机能更精通了
And it would appear their knowledge of Cybertronian bio-tech has grown more sophisticated.
可是 为什么他们要大黄蜂的零件？
But why would they want Bumblebee's part?
大黄蜂 别
Bumblebee, please.
以你目前的状况无法胜任
You are not presently equipped to handle this.
你误会了 我的朋友
You are mistaken, my friend.
我当然可以体会失去自身重要部分的痛楚
I do know what it's like to lose a vital part of oneself.
也正因此
And, as a result
我更懂得要信赖自己的团队
I know the value of putting one's faith in the strength of those around you.
我们发誓会竭尽全力让你完好如初
We vow to do everything in our power to make you whole again.
就算不能 救护车也会为你量身打造一个新…
And if not, Ratchet can just make you a new...
…什么齿轮来着？
cog-thing. Right?
我说错什么了？
What did I say?
神子! 变形齿轮是生理器官 不是随处可见的旧零件
Miko! A T-cog is a bio-mechanism, not a scrap-yard find.
如果像你想的那么容易
If it were that easy don't you think
我不早就给大黄蜂换上新的发声器了吗？
I would have replaced Bumblebee's voice-box by now?
你不是一无是处 小蜂！
You are not useless, Bee.
好吧 好吧
All right all right
我们在大黄蜂的部件找到之前都不变形
I say none of us transform until Bumblebee gets his cog back.
你的心肠很好 隔板
Your spark’s in the right place, Bulkhead.
但现在可不是自缚手脚的时候
But I don't think now was the time to be limiting ourselves.
尤其是在威震天搜寻可以毁灭世界的装置之时
Not with Megatron potentially seeking other Doomsday devices.
而我还担心机械党在利用大黄蜂的变形齿轮
And I fear not while MECH uses Bumblebee's T-cog
干他们不可告人的勾当
for their own sinister purpose.
开始第二阶段测试
Commence beta-test.
安装成功 开始扫描
Installation complete. Commencing scan.
扫描成功
Scan successful.
开始变形
Commencing transformation.
就是你们拆了倒霉的打击 并把他变成了可怜的科学实验品？
You are the ones who turned poor Breakdown into a pitiful science experiment?
没从实验中得到你们想要的吧？
Didn't learn much from the experience, did you?
这足以知道你的弱点在哪儿了 霸天虎
Enough to know where the soft spots are, Decepticon.
拜托 我已经不属于那个阵营了
Oh please. I am no longer affiliated with that entity.
再说 如果我是来替大块头寻仇的
Besides, if I were here to avenge the big lug
你早就跪地求饶了
you would be screaming for mercy by now.
你来这儿做什么？
Why are you here?
来与你们结盟
To propose an alliance.
你看 我们之间的共同点比你想象的要多
You see, we have much more in common than you might think.
我说的可不只是身上的伤痕
And I am not merely referring to our battle scars.
那么 这场交易能带给我什么好处？
What could I possibly gain from such an arrangement?
业内知识
Insider knowledge.
明智的选择
Wise choice.
变形齿轮不是技术产品 而是生理器官
Now. A T-cog isn't technology. It is biology.
这意味着它排斥一切能源 除了能量体
Which means it will reject any power source other than energon.
接着说
Go on.
能量体就是燃料
Energon is the fuel
是所有塞博特恩人的弹药和生命源泉
the ammunition and the lifeblood of all Cybertronians
无论他们是哪个阵营
whatever their affiliation.
你们和我都想得到它
You and I both want it.
现在我缺少定位它的手段
And currently I lack the means of locating it.
不过 只要我向你提供…
But once I supply you with the...
其独特的化学构成
particulars of its chemical make-up...
我们就能利用你手头的资源
we can utilise your considerable resources
探测出新的能量矿藏
to devise a means of detecting new deposits.
供我们同享
For us to share.
前提是这个供应能满足机械党的大量需求
IF the supply meets M.E.C.H.'s rather significant demand.
啊哈…想建立一支军队 是吧？
Aah... Intending to build an army, are you?
我对这样的野心可一点都不陌生
I am no stranger to ambition.
擎天柱和隔板暂时还没报告
Optimus and Bulkhead haven't reported in yet.
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee!
有消息我会告诉你的！
I will let you know the moment I hear something.
看在原始天尊的份上!
Oh for Primus' sake!
谁来给他找点事儿干 好让我专心工作？
Will someone keep him occupied so I can get some work done?!!
嘿 小蜂
Hey, Bee.
来把游戏怎么样？
How about a videogame?
不合时宜
Bad call.
对不起
Sorry.
嘿 不要紧
Hey, no big deal!
反正这游戏也很烂
That game is lame.
看看电视怎么样？
What do you say we watch some TV?
新款厄巴纳500 不仅仅会震撼你的世界
The new Urbana 500. It won't just rock your world.
还会改变你的世界
It will transform it.
汽车人没了汽车还真是糟糕
Taking the "auto-" out of an Autobot is so not a good thing.
小蜂 别这样 你没轮子也一样耀眼
Bee, c'mon! You're just as amazing without wheels!
我的意思是 速度不代表一切
I mean, speed isn't everything.
个人最佳纪录 阿尔茜！
Personal best, Arcee!
轻松打破1分20秒！
You hit 1:20 easy.
啊哦…
Uh-oh.
大黄蜂！你去哪儿？
Bumblebee! Where do you think you're going?
你不能就这样随便出去散步！
You can't just go for a walk!
我们是隐蔽行动的机器人！
We are robots in disguise.
离开基地会将你置于险境
Leaving the base in this form puts you at risk of being seen
而且暴露我们的行踪
and of us being discovered.
你就呆在这儿 直到…
You''ll just have to remain in the silo until...
是的 大黄蜂 直到我能把你治好
... yes, Bumblebee. Until I can fix you.
上车 走人
In you go.
谢谢你接我回家
Thanks for the lift home
杰克的妈妈 在…在医院里做护士
friend of Jack's Mom who is a nurse at... at... the hospital!
其他人呢？
Where are the others?
杰克在打工
Jack's at work.
神子又留堂了
Miko's in detention... again.
我还以为隔板会来
I was expecting Bulkhead.
好吧 很抱歉让你失望了 不过他在执行任务
Well, I’m sorry to disappoint but he is on watch duty.
想试试警笛开道么？
You want to ride with the siren on?
不 谢了
No, thank you.
应该没错 我要通知其他人
This could be it. I'll alert the others.
我知道你能胜任
I know you and I can handle it
不过 小蜂 没理由…
Bee, but there is no reason to...
你想证明什么？
What are you trying to prove?
救护车
Ratchet.
大黄蜂的发声器是怎么回事？
What happened to Bumblebee's voice-box?
是在战斗中 严重受损
It was... severely damaged in battle.
怎么搞的？
How?
你觉得呢？
How do you think?
当然很惨
Tragically, of course.
这发生在和平圣坛
It happened at Tyger-Pax.
（Tyger Pax 和平圣坛 代表生命的圣坛 真人电影中设定为供奉火种源的神坛)
Our brave scout was captured by Megatron's forces and interrogated.
不过他没有透露任何情报
But he refused to provide intel.
为此付出了惨重代价
And paid a grave price for his courage.
大黄蜂几乎成为了一堆废铁
Bumblebee was left for scrap.
不过汽车人部队找到了他 并送进了救护站
But Autobot troops found him and evacuated him to a triage facility.
一个战地医生稳住了他的伤势
Where a field medic managed to stabilize his condition.
所以 大黄蜂的性命多亏了那位战地医生？
So, we owe Bumblebee's life to that field medic?
从某个角度来说可以这么认为
That's one way of looking at it, I suppose.
不过那个医生…本可以做得更好
Though the medic... could have done better.
安全
Clear.
天晓得我怎么会帮你这么干
I still don't know how you talked me into this.
你比神子还不安分
You're worse than Miko.
好好好 我知道
Yeah-yeah-yeah, I know.
不是每次任务都需要高速追击
Not every mission ends in a high-speed pursuit
但你要是不能…
but without your...
好 我不说了
Fine. I'll drop it.
不过如果擎天柱发现了 别说这是我的主意
But if Optimus finds out, this was not my idea.
信号来源就是那儿
Signal's coming from over there.
正朝我们过来 还很快
And it's coming our way, fast!
有本事就来抓我啊！
Catch me if you can!
我去抓住他！
I'll get him!
好吧 你去！
Okay. You get him!
你在锻炼身体么？
Sporting of you?
不准备打爆我的轮胎么？
You're not even gotta try and shoot up my tires?
大黄蜂 你那传说中的马力呢？
Bumblebee! Where is your famous horse-power?
让我看看你的速度！
Show me some speed!
那个老爷车是啥情况？
What is with the rent-a-car?!
我也想陪你套会儿圈圈…
I'd stick around and do some doughnuts around you...
不过我现在有货要送
But I have a delivery to make.